Finding Aid for the Kenneth Rexroth Papers LSC.0175
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975); 39 boxes (19.5 linear ft.).
  - Subseries 1A: A-Z, 1853-1979 (bulk 1950-1975); 35 boxes.
    - Harper and Row (Harper's Magazine)., 1953-1969.; 36 items. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from readers in response to Rexroth's article on "The New American Poets."
    - Harper's Bazaar--Harrison, James., 1951-1975.; 16 items. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Harrison, Lou., 1970-1973.; 19 items. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Correspondence and ephemera regarding Chinese music ensemble with William Cohio.
    - Harry N. Abrams--Harry Walker, Inc., 1959-1968.; 34 items. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Hart--Harvard Law School Forum., 1945-1966.; 28 items. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Harvard University Press--Henry., 1947-1975.; 65 items. (Box 9, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Allen Tate (editor at Henry Holt and Company).
    - Herder and Herder, Inc. (folder 1 of 2)., 1968-1970.; ca. 100 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence between Justus George Lawler (editor) and Rexroth.
    - Herder and Herder, Inc. (folder 2 of 2)., 1971-1972.; ca. 100 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Hering--Hill and Wang, Inc., 1945-1972.; 68 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Includes a partial letter from Hilaire Hiler, and 1 letter from his son regarding an exhibition of his father's work.
    - Hill Publishing Company--Holmes., 1937-1973.; 73 items. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.--Humphreys., 1946-1974.; 62 items. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from E.R. Hughes.
    - Humphries, Rolfe., 1936-1952.; 9 items. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hungry i--Hyman., 1948-1973.; 48 items. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Idaho State College--Ingersoll and Brennan., 1953-1971.; 29 items. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence from David Ignatow.
    - Ingerson--Insight., 1949-1968.; 21 items. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Institute of International Education., 1949-1968.; 25 items. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Intercultural Publications., 1952-1958.; 62 items. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      See also Laughlin, James.
    - Interim--Izzo., 1937-1974.; 39 items. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - J. Barth & Co.--Jack Hampton Agency., 1957-1964.; 10 items. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Jack's Record Cellar--Jacobsen., 1945-1965.; 15 items. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Jacobson, Eli., 1946-1951.; 11 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Jacobson, James--Japanese American Philatelic Society., 1929-1971.; 24 items. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Jarreau, Dianne., 1965-1975.; 53 items. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Jayne--John Brown Society., 1951-1971.; 24 items. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation., 1968-1972.; 6 items. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Johns Hopkins Press--Jones, Frank., 1951-1974.; 23 items. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Jones, Helen--Justema., 1955-1973.; 42 items. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Kadeski--Kaplanski., 1945-1972.; 24 items. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Kapp--Kast., 1940-1969.; 12 items. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Katagiri, Yuzuru., 1967-1975.; 21 items. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Katz--Keene., 1960-1974.; 19 items. (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Kayak editors (little magazine).
    - Kees, Weldon., 1940-1961.; 14 items. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Keeter--Kernan., 1955-1975.; 28 items. (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Includes letters with Hugh Kenner.
    - Kerouac, Jack., 1956-1958.; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Kerr--Kitaj., 1946-1975.; 36 items. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with Lincoln Kirstein and Ronald B. Kitaj.
    - Kitasono, Katue., 1948-1967.; 35 items. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kitch--Knudson., 1950-1975.; 27 items. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Includes business correspondence with Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. (Harold Strauss and William Koshland).
    - Koch--Kozlik., 1940-1975.; 55 items. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Includes correspondence with Vivienne Koch and Richard Kostelanetz.
    - KPFA (folder 1 of 4)., 1953-1959.; 55 items. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - KPFA (folder 2 of 4)., 1960-1963.; 75 items. (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Includes memos and correspondence regarding KPFA and the FCC and House un-American Activities Committee.
    - KPFA (folder 3 of 4)., 1964-1969.; 38 items. (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Includes letters and memos regarding 1964 KPFA strike.
    - KPFA (folder 4 of 4)., 1970-1973.; 56 items. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - KPFK--Kurtz., 1946-1974.; 52 items. (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence from KQED television.
    - Kusske, Jan-Louise., 1967-1969.; 18 items. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Kwock, Chan H., 1948-1967.; ca. 35 items. (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Includes numerous translations of Chinese poems.
    - L.A.--Lafayette., 1953-1973.; 10 items. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Lagercrantz, Olof., 1958-1972.; 16 items. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Lagorio--Lal., 1964-1967.; 5 items. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Lamantia, Philip., 1947-1952.; 8 items. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Lamar--Larson., 1947-1974.; 25 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence from Jay Landesman and Dan Langton.
    - Larsson, Raymond E.F. (folder 1 of 3)., 1936-1946.; 47 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes handwritten copies and drafts of poems, and 27 drawings in pencil and colored pencil, some mounted.
    - Larsson, Raymond E.F. (folder 2 of 3)., 1947-1950.; 50 items. (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Includes handwritten copies and drafts of poems, and 41 drawings in pencil, colored pencil, and ink.
    - Larsson, Raymond E.F. (folder 3 of 3)., 1951-1967.; 42 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Numerous handwritten copies of poems, including a composition book of poems dedicated to Rexroth on his birthday, 1954.
    - Latitudinarianists Anonymous--Lauden., 1961-1966.; 12 items. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Laughlin, James (folder 1 of 3)., 1937-1948.; 105 items. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      See also New Directions and Intercultural Publications.
    - Laughlin, James (folder 2 of 3)., 1949-1957.; 98 items. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Laughlin, James (folder 3 of 3)., 1958-1965.; 119 items. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Includes some undated correspondence.
    - Laughlin, Margaret--Lehmusoksa., 1937-1971.; 44 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Includes letters from League of American Writers concerning Spanish Civil War; letters from George Ledge and Gershon Legman
    - Leite, George., 1944-1947.; 17 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
      See also Circle.
    - Lemming--Lenoir., 1952-1973.; 11 items. (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Cornel Lengyel.
    - Leonard, George., 1958-1969.; 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Look Magazine.
    - Leone--Leverant., 1941-1974.; 17 items. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Levertov, Denise., 1947-1972.; 56 items. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Levi--Liberation., 1941-1974.; 41 items. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Libertarian League--Linder., 1937 -1974.; 36 items. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Lindsay Drummond Ltd.--Lipton, Dean., 1947-1968.; 20 items. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Lipton, Lawrence (folder 1 of 2)., 1952-1953.; 64 items. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Lipton, Lawrence (folder 2 of 2)., 1954-1957.; 40 items. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Lish--London Authors., 1952-1973.; 34 items. (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Includes letters from Gordon Lish.
    - Lonergan Congress., 1969-1970.; 22 items. (Box 14, Folder 9)
      For essays on Lonergan written by participants in the Congress, see Subseries 4B.
    - Longview Foundation--Lovegrove., 1957-1973.; 34 items. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Lowenfels, Walter and Lilian., 1937-1971.; 57 items. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Loy--Lundquist., 1945-1966.; 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Includes 1 letter from Mina Loy.
    - Lundt, Helen., 1936-1970.; 45 items. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Lurie--Lynes & Sons., 1953-1975.; 24 items. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Maas--MacLeod, Joseph., 1946-1975.; 23 items. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Hugh MacDiarmid.
    - MacLeod, Norman., 1945-1956.; 20 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Macmillan Company., 1937-1971.; 40 items. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Macomber-Madden., 1952-1968.; 5 items. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mademoiselle., 1957-1966.; 41 items. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Madge--Magnum Pubs., 1947-1970.; 7 items. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Mahony, Patrick., 1968-1970.; 34 items. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Maierhofer--Malandaras., 1956-1969.; 10 items. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Malanga, Gerard., 1966-1973.; 16 items. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Malkin--Marcus., 1948-1974.; 35 items. (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence from Jerre Mangione.
    - Mardersteig, Giovanni., 1948-1959.; 11 items. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Margolis--Marshall., 1948-1974.; 34 items. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Marte--Martzuiak., 1948-1972.; 23 items. (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Includes correspondence with James J. Martin.
    - Masin, Laura., 1972-1975.; 25 items. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Mason--Matthews., 1952-1973.; 29 items. (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Includes correspondence from Jeffrey Masson.
    - Mattick, Paul., 1941-1955.; 19 items. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Maule--Mazer., 1933-1974.; 28 items. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - McAdou--McAllaster., 1971-1972.; 6 items. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - McAlmon, Robert., 1931-1941.; 25 items. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - McAteer-McGrath., 1947-1971.; 41 items. (Box 15, Folder 21)
      Includes letters from Michael McClure and Thomas McGrath.
    - McGraw Hill Book Co., 1953-1975.; 26 items. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - McGregor--McWilliams., 1936-1973.; 43 items. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Meagher--Melton., 1950-1968.; 19 items. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Meltzer, David., 1969-1970.; 12 items. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Meltzer, Milton--Mezey., 1953-1974.; 34 items. (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Robert Mezey.
    - Michel--Miller, David., 1936-1974.; 14 items. (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from Midwest (see also Le Sueur, Meridel).
    - Miller, Henry., 1944-1957.; 35 items. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Jim--Mittag., 1945-1971.; 51 items. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Mock--Monley., 1947-1975.; 17 items. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Monohan, Minnie and Paul., 1947-1954.; 35 items. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Monroe--Montgomery Art Guild., 1931-1971.; 12 items. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Montgomery, John., 1940-1973.; 53 items. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Monty--Moran., 1931-1971.; 31 items. (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Marianne Moore and Nicholas Moore.
    - Moreau--Morrison., 1941-1969.; 28 items. (Box 16, Folder 13)
      Includes letters from Edwin Morgan.
    - Morrow, Felix., 1968-1974.; 15 items. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Morse--Moyer., 1964-1975.; 32 items. (Box 16, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Stanley Moss.
    - Mt. Diablo Peace Center--Myers., 1937-1972.; 33 items. (Box 16, Folder 16)
      Includes letters from A.J. Muste.
    - Nakazawa--Natchez., 1952-1974.; 23 items. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Kimiko Nakazawa and George Nasir.
    - The Nation (folder 1 of 3)., 1952-1957.; 101 items. (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Nation correspondence includes letters from Carey McWilliams, and other editors.
    - The Nation (folder 2 of 3)., 1958-1960.; 95 items. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - The Nation (folder 3 of 3)., 1961-1972.; 99 items. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People--National Educational Television., 1958-1971.; 21 items. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities., 1970-1972.; 15 items. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters., 1950-1974.; 65 items. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - National Library Week Committee--National Poetry Association., 1956-1967.; 6 items. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - National Poetry Festival., 1962.; 21 items. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - National Poetry Foundation--Nearing., 1959-1975.; 16 items. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Neavill, Jonnie Kay., 1970-1974.; 16 items. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Nebenzahl--Netboy., 1946-1973.; 30 items. (Box 17, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Truman Nelson (2), Howard Nemerov (4), and Gogo Nesbit.
    - Netherlands Office for Foreign Student Relations--Neville, Tove., 1951-1967.; 14 items. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - New American Library--New China Daily Press., 1952-1971.; 66 items. (Box 17, Folder 14)
      Bulk from New American Library.
    - New Directions., 1944-1973. (Box 18, Box 19)
      See also Laughlin, James. Files arranged in chronological order, except for box 19, folder 12, which contains royalites and invoices from the 1940s through 1965.
    - New Japanese Literature--New Politics., 1937-1972.; 27 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Includes letters with publications The New Leader and New Masses.
    - New Republic., 1935-1966.; 31 items. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - New Rivers Press--New York Review of Books., 1947-1975.; 54 items. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - New York Times--New York Times Book Review., 1951-1971.; 99 items. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - New York University Press--Nicholas., 1948-1962.; 31 items. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Nichols--Nydegger., 1947-1973.; 56 items. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Oakland Municipal Art Museum--O'Connor., 1940-1974.; 9 items. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Oden, Gloria., 1960-1975.; 54 items. (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - O'Donohue--Olson., 1951-1970.; 22 items. (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Includes letters from Tillie Olsen and Charles Olson.
    - Oltarsh--Orebaugh., 1947-1967.; 46 items. (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from Honor Orebaugh
    - Oregon State--Other Scenes., 1948-1967.; 36 items. (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Gil Orlovitz and Peter Orlovsky.
    - Otto Rank Association--Oyez., 1955-1973.; 32 items. (Box 20, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Oxford UP.
    - Pacific Academy of the Arts--Palmatier., 1946-1975.; 35 items. (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Includes a letter from Ron Padgett.
    - Palmer, Charlene and David., 1951-1957.; 18 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Palmer, Phil--Parkinson, Kathy., 1950-1968.; 21 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Includes a letter from Robel Paris, and letters from Helen Wolff (as editor of Pantheon Books).
    - Parkinson, Tom and Ariel., 1947-1974.; 36 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Parks--Partridge., 1936-1973.; 10 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Includes letters with Philip Rahv and Clement Greenberg (as editors of Partisan Review; see also Greenberg).
    - Patchen, Kenneth and Miriam., 1948-1961.; 24 items. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Patronato--Payton., 1948-1971.; 32 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from Robert Payne.
    - Peace News--P.E.N., 1948-1972.; 40 items. (Box 21, Folder 7)
      Includes typescript by Yves Pellec.
    - Pendle Hill--Perspective., 1946-1975.; 56 items. (Box 21, Folder 8)
      Includes letters from Magda Ferrer Peralta and Mona Van Duyn (as editor of Perspective).
    - Perspectives., 1952-1955.; 40 items. (Box 21, Folder 9)
      See also James Laughlin and New Directions.
    - Petersen--PHP Institute., 1953-1974.; 28 items. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Piantanida--Pizzati., 1945-1974.; 34 items. (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Marshall Pidgeon.
    - Place--Planz., 1957-1969.; 7 items. (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from Arturo Serrano Plaja.
    - Playboy., 1960-1972.; ca. 32 items. (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Includes typescripts of articles, newspaper clippings of research.
    - Playhouse Repertory Theater--Ploughshares., 1956-1974.; 14 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with Kermit Sheets, director of Playhouse Rep. Theater.
    - Pocket Books--Poet Lore., 1938-1969.; 12 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Poetry., 1931-1968.; 44 items. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence from Harriet Monroe and Henry Rago, editors.
    - Poetry Center of the YM and YWHA--Poetry Singapore., 1940-1969.; 37 items. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      See also Poets & Writers.
    - Poetry Society of Alaska--Poetry Society of America., 1948-1965.; 13 items. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Poets & Writers--Pokrass., 1961-1972.; 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Politics--Porter, Arabel., 1946-1972.; 34 items. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Porter, Bern., 1946-1968.; 20 items. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Porter, J. Frank--Potts., 1957-1973.; 26 items. (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Includes a letter from Charles Potts. See also Netboy, Anthony (Portland State College).
    - Pound, Ezra., 1931-1954.; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Powell--Poze., 1957-1973.; 11 items. (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Lawrence Clark Powell. See also University of California, Los Angeles, Library.
    - Prado--Prudhommeaux., 1941-1973.; 46 items. (Box 22, Folder 12)
      Includes a letter from John Hyde Preston.
    - Purcell--Putnam's., 1931-1968.; 26 items. (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Includes letters from James Purdy
    - Pym-Randall Press--Pyramid Publications., 1964-1973.; 43 items. (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Bulk of letters from Pym-Randall Press.
    - Quadrangle Books--Quintana., 1962-1974.; 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - R.G. Davis Mime Troupe--Rabinowitch., 1931-1972.; 11 items. (Box 22, Folder 16)
      Includes letters from Joseph Rabinowitch.
    - Radcliffe--Raimi., 1944-1975.; 22 items. (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Rainbird McLean Ltd.--Randall., 1928-1974.; 35 items. (Box 22, Folder 18)
      Includes letters from Kathleen Raine and Carl Rakosi.
    - Random House, Inc., 1952-1971.; 40 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Ranger--Rath., 1941-1965.; 11 items. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Includes one letter from John Crowe Ransom.
    - Rather, L. J., 1955-1971.; 21 items. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Rather, P.--Ray, George., 1931-1974.; 9 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Ray, Man--Rayter., 1945-1954.; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from Man Ray and Bernard Raymund.
    - Read, Hobart., 1946-1958.; 11 items. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Reader's Subscription Inc.--Redwood Ranchers., 1947-1972.; 22 items. (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Includes letters from David Redman.
    - Reed & Harris--Reed College., 1945-1972.; 21 items. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Reed, Mary., 1853-1905.; 15 items. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Letters from Rexroth's grandmother, Mary Reed. Includes letters from Rexroth's great-great-grandmother to his great-grandmother, Mary O'Conner.
    - Reed (The)--Resist., 1950-1974.; 24 items. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Retort., 1941-1960.; 37 items. (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Holley Cantine and Dachine Rainer.
    - Rexroth, Andrée., ca. 1940.; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Rexroth, Katharine., ca. 1960-1973.; 32 items. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Abels, C.--Kavanaugh., 1941-1975.; 30 items. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Kees, Weldon., 1939-1942.; 15 items. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Lagercrantz--Newsom., 1940-1968.; 7 items. (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Rausom--Wolfert., 1937-1975.; 22 items. (Box 23, Folder 17)
      Includes a letter to Selden Rodman.
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to Zukof sky, Louis., 1929-1931.; 20 items. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth [WWII conscription file]., 1940-1942.; 12 items. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth to unidentified correspondents., 1931-1975.; ca. 60 items. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Rexroth, Marie (folder 1 of 4)., 1937-1946.; ca. 50 items. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Rexroth, Marie (folder 2 of 4)., 1948-1957.; ca. 80 items. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      Includes a copy of divorce papers (1955).
    - Rexroth, Marie (folder 3 of 4)., 1958-1966.; ca. 60 items. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Rexroth, Marie (folder 4 of 4)., 1967-1973.; ca. 50 items. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Rexroth, Marthe (folder 1 of 3)., 1947-1955.; ca. 100 items. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Rexroth, Marthe (folder 2 of 3)., 1956-1958.; ca. 70 items. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Rexroth, Marthe (folder 3 of 3)., 1959-1962.; ca. 50 items. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Rexroth, Mary (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 1955-1964.; ca. 50 items. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Rexroth, Mary (folder 2 of 2)., ca. 1965-1973.; ca. 60 items. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Rexroth--Other., 1941-1961.; 29 items. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Assorted letters to Kenneth Rexroth from people with the same surname, usually inquiring about common ancestry. Includes letters from Byron Rexroth, Carrie Rexroth, Franz von Rexroth, Grace Rexroth (Kenneth's aunt), Gunther Rexroth, Helyn Rexroth, Karl Rexroth and Mr. & Mrs. Otis Rexroth, and Virginia Rexroth.
    - Reynolds--Richard Fulton Inc., 1958-1975.; 11 items. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Richards, Charles and Janet., 1947-1959.; 21 items. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Richards, Howad--Rizzardi., 1936-1973.; 21 items. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Robbins, Duren--Robertson, John-David., 1950-1975.; 27 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Robinson, Bob [Robert]., 1964-1973.; 30 items. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Robinson, William--Rodell., 1946-1970.; 27 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Roditi, Edouard (folder 1 of 6)., 1945-1948.; 5 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Roditi, Edouard (folder 2 of 6)., ca. 1952.; 10 items. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Roditi, Edouard (folder 3 of 6)., 1953.; 7 items. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Roditi, Edouard (folder 4 of 6)., 1954-1964.; 9 items. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Roditi, Edouard (folder 5 of 6)., 1966.; 19 items. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Roditi, Edouard (folder 6 of 6)., 1966-1969.; 35 items. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Rodman, Selden., 1945-1955.; 41 items. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Rodriguez--Rougue River Gorge., 1951-1970.; 7 items. (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Theodore Roethke.
    - Rolfe--Rosenzweig., 1945-1973.; 16 items. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Roskolenko, Harry., 1944-1972.; 39 items. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Rosso--Roz., 1946-1974.; 24 items. (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Rubin--Rubinstein., 1959-1969.; 31 items. (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Ruff--Rummel., 1945-1958.; 12 items. (Box 26, Folder 16)
      Includes letters from Muriel Rykeyser.
    - Rush, Norman., 1952-1956.; 19 items. (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Russ--Ryan., 1937-1975.; 28 items. (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Sachs--San Luis Bay Inn., 1955-1974.; 50 items. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco Magazine., 1965-1974.; 36 items. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Art Institute--San Francisco Arts Resources Development Committee., 1962-1967.; 25 items. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco Association for Mental Health--San Francisco Bay Guardian., 1960-1972.; 48 items. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - San Francisco Café Theatre--San Francisco College for Women., 1951-1972.; 16 items. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - San Francisco Examiner., 1960-1967.; ca. 25 items. (Box 27, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from editors, in addition to letters from readers responding to his articles.
    - San Francisco Foundation--San Francisco Opera., 1948-1969.; 25 items. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - San Francisco Planning & Urban Renewal Association--San Francisco Public Library., 1952-1970.; 31 items. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - San Francisco Redevelopment Agency--San Francisco Youth Association., 1950-1974.; 54 items. (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Includes letters from San Francisco State College.
    - San Jose Public Library--Saturday Evening Post., 1947-1975.; 39 items. (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Includes 1 letter from William Saroyan.
    - Saturday Review., 1957-1968.; 67 items. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Saturday Review--Classics Revisited (folder 1 of 2)., 1964-1966.; 63 items. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Saturday Review--Classics Revisited (folder 2 of 2)., 1967-1970.; 107 items. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Sausalito Little Theatre--Savage., 1947-1962.; 42 items. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Includes 40 letters from Derek Savage.
    - Saxton--Schwartz., 1948-1974.; 39 items. (Box 28, Folder 5)